Finding Aid for John W. Aldridge papers 1943-2007
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
John W. Aldridge papers 1943-2007 1950-2000
Aldridge, John W.
2009135 Aa 2
University of Michigan professor of English (1964-1991), director of the Hopwood Program (1975-1988), USIA Special Ambassador to Germany (1972-1973), and esteemed literary critic. Papers (1943-2004) include extensive personal and professional correspondence, published and unpublished manuscripts and writings, notes and lecture materials for courses taught, USIA program materials and correspondence, topical files, photographs, and audio-visual recordings.
14.4 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Accession received through Patricia Aldridge in 2009 (donor no. 10178 ).
Periodic additions to the records expected.
The Aldridge papers are open for research except for certain records restricted by statute or university policy.
The Aldridge papers includes restricted material in the following categories:
Student Records -- Box 15
John (Jack) Watson Aldridge was an esteemed literary critic and professor of English at the University of Michigan (1964-1991). As a critic, Aldridge devoted himself to what he called "the ideal of creative independence and free critical dissent which has come down to us in the central tradition of American thought and letters," (Current Biography, 1958) and throughout his career he commented upon and critiqued many of the twentieth century's most important writers, including Joseph Heller, Norman Mailer, Ralph Ellison, John Horne Burns, Malcolm Cowley, Arthur Miller, Gore Vidal, Wright Morris, Saul Bellow, William Styron, Philip Roth, and Truman Capote, many of whom he also counted as his friends.
John W. Aldridge was born on September 26, 1922 in Sioux City, Iowa to Walther Copher and Nell Madge (Watson) Aldridge. Aldridge spent his early years in Iowa, until the age of twelve, when the family moved to Chattanooga, Tennessee. Aldridge attend the University of Chattanooga (now the University of Tennessee at Chattanooga) from 1940 to 1943, and studied English during the summer of 1942 at Middlebury College's School of English at Bread Loaf in Vermont, prior to enlisting in the Army and serving in World War II as an infantry rifleman and information specialist (July 1943- August 1945). Following his military service, during which he earned a Bronze Star and five battle stars for Normandy, Northern France, Rhineland, Central Europe, and the Ardennes, Aldridge enrolled at the University of California at Berkeley in 1946. At Berkeley, Aldridge worked as the editor of the school's Occident literary magazine, and earned his Bachelor of Arts in 1947.
Prior to coming to the University of Michigan, Aldridge was a lecturer and later assistant professor at the University of Vermont (1948-1950, 1954-1955), a lecturer for the Christian Gauss Seminars in Criticism at Princeton University (1953-1955), and a visiting professor at Sarah Lawrence College (1956-1957), Queens College of the City of New York (1957), and New York University (1958). Aldridge also served as a Fulbright Lecturer at the University of Munich (1958-1959) and the University of Copenhagen (1962-1963), and as critic-in-residence and visiting professor at Hollins College (1959-1962).
Aldridge came to the University of Michigan in 1964 as a visiting associate professor of English language and literature, and was promoted to professor in 1965. Aldridge was well-known at Michigan for his lectures on the contemporary novel, and his students heralded his teaching abilities. In addition to guiding the scholarship of scores of graduate and undergraduate students, Aldridge also served as the chair of the editorial board of the Michigan Quarterly Review (1978-1992), and director of the Hopwood Program at the University of Michigan and chair of the Hopwood Writing Awards Committee (1975-1988).
In addition to traditional academic appointments, Aldridge also served as a Special Ambassador for American Studies at the American Embassy in Bonn, Germany (1972-1973), as a book commentator and reviewer for "The MacNeil/Lehrer News Hour" on public television, and as a book critic for the New York Herald Tribune Book Week (1965-1966) and the Saturday Review (1970-1979). Aldridge was also the recipient of a Rockefeller Humanities Fellowship for the 1976-1977 academic year.
Aldridge was an active writer and critic throughout his career, publishing numerous essays and book reviews in a wide range of publications, including Harper's Magazine, Saturday Review, New York Times Book Review, Partisan Review, Nation, Playboy, Commentary, The Sewanee Review, Michigan Quarterly Review, The American Scholar, Chronicles, Esquire, Chicago Tribune Book World, New Republic, New York Herald Tribune Book Week, and Life. Aldridge was also a co-founder, with author Vance Bourjaily, in 1951 of Discovery magazine, an influential literary magazine published by Pocket Books.
In addition to writing regular essays and book reviews, Aldridge was the author of numerous works of literary criticism, a novel The Party at Cranton, and a sociological study of youth culture, In the Country of the Young. Aldridge considered his literary criticism of contemporary writers his most important work, however, telling Contemporary Authors (Gale, 2002), "I am, and have always wanted to be, a critic of the literature of my own time. With the exception of my novel, The Party at Cranton, and an informal sociological study, In the Country of the Young, my books have all been studies of current literature, primarily American fiction. I have never considered criticism in any sense a minor or inferior literary form, and one of my ambitions has been to write criticism in such a way that it can be seen to have the qualities of style, structure, and dramatic development which are normally associated with fiction." Aldridge placed such primacy on his critical works that he devoted a substantial portion of his unpublished autobiography, Against the Current, to discussions of the intellectual bases of his criticism and the sometimes laudatory, sometimes negative, reception it received.
Aldridge's first book of criticism After the Lost Generation (1951), was one of the first critical treatment of major post-war writers such as Norman Mailer, John Horne Burns, Truman Capote, Gore Vidal, and others, and earned Aldridge high acclaim in the literary world and established his reputation as one of the foremost literary critics of his generation. When After the Lost Generation was reprinted in 1985, Norman Mailer wrote in the "Introduction," that "Aldridge was the nearest guideline to absolute truth that the working novelist had in my young days. I wonder if there was ever a critic who understood any better the roots of the problems that beset the novelists of his own generation." Aldridge's literary criticism incited strong reactions amongst those in the literary world, with Gore Vidal including him in a list of "literary gangsters." Aldridge, however, relished the impassioned responses to his work, saying, "I suppose I have had what is called a 'controversial' career. All my books have provoked argument and discussion. And, I am pleased that this should be so, for I function best in an atmosphere of controversy and would very probably die if I were ever read with indifference." (World Authors, 1950-1970, 1975)
During the long course of his career Aldridge contributed introductions, forewords, and essays to numerous works, in addition to serving as an editor for Critiques and Essays on Modern Fiction (1952) and Selected Stories of P.G. Wodehouse (1958). Aldridge was also the author of nine books: After the Lost Generation (1951), In Search of Heresy: American Literature in an Age of Conformity (1956), The Party at Cranton (1960), Time to Murder and Create (1966), In the Country of the Young (1970), The Devil in the Fire (1972), The American Novel and the Way We Live Now (1983), Talents and Technicians (1992), and Classics and Contemporaries (1992).
Aldridge retired as an University of Michigan professor of English in 1991. While in retirement with emeritus status (1991-2007), Aldridge maintained an active scholarly lifestyle and continued producing articles and book reviews, as well as writing two unpublished manuscripts In the Company of Lions, a work of criticism, and Against the Current, a memoir. Married five times and the father of five sons, John W. Aldridge died February 7, 2007.
The John W. Aldridge Papers document the professional and personal life of one of the twentieth century's most distinguished literary critics, and a longtime University of Michigan professor of English. The records in this collection measure 14.4 linear feet, and date from 1943 to 2006, with the majority of the records from the period 1950 to 2000. They are primarily comprised of correspondence, lectures and addresses, teaching materials, writings and publications, research notes, clippings, program and topical files, and are arranged into nine series: Biographical Materials, Correspondence, Hopwood Awards Program, Lectures and Addresses, Scrapbooks, Teaching, USIA/Special Ambassador, Writings, and Audio-Visual Materials.
Subjects:
American literature--20th century--History and criticism.; Criticism--United States.; University of Michigan. Dept. of English Language and Literature.; University of Michigan. Avery Hopwood and Jule Hopwood Prizes.; University of Michigan--Faculty.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
American literature--20th century--History and criticism.; Criticism--United States.; Authors, American--20th century.; World War, 1939-1945.; University of Michigan--Faculty.
Subjects - Sound Recordings:
Mailer, Norman.; Styron, William, 1925-2006.
Contributors:
Blackmur, R.P. (Richard P.), 1904-1965.; Buckley, William F. (William Frank), Jr., 1925-2008.; Cowley, Malcolm, 1898-1989.; Ellison, Ralph.; Gaddis, William, 1922-1998.; Heller, Joseph.; Mailer, Norman.; Miller, Arthur, 1915-2005.; Nin, Anaís, 1903-1977.; Morris, Wright, 1910-1998.; Styron, William, 1925-2006.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Sound recordings.; Videotapes.
- Biographical Materials 1945-2000
  The Biographical Materials series, 1943-2000 (0.25 linear ft.), contains materials on the Aldridge family genealogy, Aldridge's veteran status, Aldridge's fifty-year high school reunion, and undated photographs that appear to span the period from 1943 to 1985, approximately.
  - Aldridge Genealogy (Box 1)
  - Aldridge, Nell (Box 1)
  - Class Reunion (Box 1)
  - Curriculum Vitae and Profile (Box 1)
  - Photographs, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Veteran Records (Box 1)
- Correspondence 1943-2006
  The Correspondence series, 1943-2006 (3 linear ft.), contains correspondence both to and from John W. Aldridge over a 66 year span. The series is organized into subseries chronologically by year, as well as by correspondent. In addition to personal and business letters, this series also includes a subseries of letters of recommendation Aldridge wrote on his students and colleagues' behalf. Noteworthy materials in this series include a 53 year correspondence with Aldridge's friend Grant Genung and correspondence with four of Aldridge's wives, as well as original and photocopied letters from William J. Buckley, Jr., John Dos Passos, Ralph Ellison, William Gaddis, Donald Hall, Joseph Heller, Norman Mailer, Bernard Malamud, Arthur Miller, Wright Morris, Anäis Nin, William Styron, Lionel Trilling, John Updike, Gore Vidal, Kurt Vonnegut, Robert Penn Warren, Tom Wolfe, and P.G. Wodehouse.
  Researchers should note that while much of the correspondence in the John W. Aldridge Papers can be found in the correspondence series, additional correspondence is located in the Hopwood Awards Program, Lectures and Addresses, Teaching, USIA/Special Ambassador, and Writings series.
  - By Year
    - 1945 (Box 1)
    - 1947 (Box 1)
    - 1948 (Box 1)
    - 1949 (Box 1)
    - 1950 (Box 1)
    - 1951 (Box 1)
    - 1952 (Box 1)
    - 1953 (Box 1)
    - 1954 (Box 1)
    - 1955 (Box 1)
    - 1956 (Box 1)
    - 1957 (Box 1)
    - 1958 (Box 1)
    - 1959 (Box 1)
    - 1960 (Box 1)
    - 1961 (Box 1)
    - 1962, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - 1963, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - 1964 (Box 1)
    - 1965 (Box 1)
    - 1966 (Box 1)
    - 1967 (Box 1)
    - 1968 (Box 1)
    - 1969 (Box 2)
    - 1970 (Box 2)
    - 1971 (Box 2)
    - 1972 (Box 2)
    - 1973 (Box 2)
    - 1974 (Box 2)
    - 1975 (Box 2)
    - 1976 (Box 2)
    - 1977 (Box 2)
    - 1978 (Box 2)
    - 1979 (Box 2)
    - 1980 (Box 2)
    - 1981 (Box 2)
    - 1982 (Box 2)
    - 1983 (Box 2)
    - 1984 (Box 2)
    - 1985 (Box 2)
    - 1986 (Box 2)
    - 1987 (Box 2)
    - 1988 (Box 2)
    - 1990s (Box 2)
    - 2000-2004 (Box 2)
    - Undated (Box 2)
  - By Correspondent
    - Agnew, Spiro (Box 2)
    - Aldridge, Alexandra (Box 2)
    - Aldridge, Henry (Box 2)
    - Aldridge, Jeremy (Box 2)
    - Aldridge, John W. (correspondence to Grant Genung) 1943-1953 (Box 2)
    - Aldridge, Lanice (Box 2)
    - Aldridge, Leslie (Box 2)
    - Aldridge, Patricia (Box 2)
    - Aldridge, Pieter (Box 2)
    - Aldridge, Stephen (Box 2)
    - Allen, Steve (Box 2)
    - Blackmur, R.P. (Richard Palmer) (Box 2)
    - Bowles, Paul (Box 2)
    - Brooks, Van Wyck (Box 2)
    - Brossard, Chandler (Box 2)
    - Buckley, William F. Jr. (Box 2)
    - Cochran, Robert (Box 2)
    - Cowley, Malcolm (Box 2)
    - Dickey, James (Box 2)
    - Dos Passos, John (Box 2)
    - Ellison, Ralph (Box 2)
    - Erbe, Pamela (Box 2)
    - Fleming, Thomas (Box 2)
    - Gaddis, William (Box 3)
    - Gaiser, Carolyn (Box 3)
    - Genung, Grant, 12 folders
      - 1949-1954 (Box 3)
      - 1960 (Box 3)
      - 1970 (Box 3)
      - 1971 (Box 3)
      - 1972 (Box 3)
      - 1973 (Box 3)
      - 1975 (Box 3)
      - 1976 (Box 3)
      - 1977-1978 (Box 3)
      - 1980-1989 (Box 3)
      - 1990-1994 (Box 3)
      - 2001-2002 (Box 3)
    - Genung, Lorraine (Box 3)
    - Gold, Herbert (Box 3)
    - Hall, Donald (Box 3)
    - Hebel, Udo (Box 3)
    - Heller, Joseph (Box 3)
    - Horowitz, Glen (Box 3)
    - Kazin, Alfred (Box 3)
    - Knoll, Robert (Box 3)
    - Kostelantz, Richard (Box 3)
    - Kumin, Maxine (Box 3)
    - Leclair, Tom (Box 3)
    - Leigh, Colston (Box 3)
    - Lennon, J. Michael (Box 3)
    - Lucid, Robert (Box 3)
    - MacDonald, John D. (Box 3)
    - Mailer, Norman (Box 3)
    - Malamud, Bernard (Box 3)
    - Manchester, William (Box 3)
    - McCauley, Gerard, 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Miller, Arthur (Box 3)
    - Morris, Wright (Box 3)
    - Ndongo, Oumar (Box 3)
    - New York Times Book Review (Box 3)
    - Nin, Anäis (Box 3)
    - Panichas, George (Box 3)
    - Pritchett, V.S. (Box 3)
    - Ramsey, Paul (Box 3)
    - Styron, William (Box 3)
    - Targ, William (Box 3)
    - Tate, Allen (Box 3)
    - Tomkins, Calvin (Box 3)
    - Trilling, Lionel (Box 3)
    - Updike, John (Box 3)
    - Vidal, Gore (Box 3)
    - Vonnegut, Kurt (Box 3)
    - Warren, Robert Penn (Box 3)
    - Willingham, Calder (Box 3)
    - Wolfe, Tom (Box 3)
    - Wodehouse, P.G. (Box 3)
  - Letters of Recommendation
    - Colleague Recommendations (Box 4)
    - Student Recommendations, 4 folders (Box 15)
      [SR RESTRICTED until July 1 2079 ]
- Hopwood Awards Program 1964-2000
  The records in the Hopwood Awards Program series, 1964-2000 (0.25 linear ft.), document Aldridge's work with the University of Michigan's Hopwood writing program. The series contains administrative files, program materials for the fiftieth anniversary of the Hopwood Festival, and Aldridge's introductory and welcome addresses for Hopwood speakers, including Joan Didion, E.L. Doctorow, William Gaddis, Joseph Heller, Lewis Lapham, Norman Mailer, Bernard Malamud, Walker Percy, and Tom Wolfe, among others.
  - Administrative (Box 4)
  - Hopwood Festival/50th Anniversary (Box 4)
  - Hopwood Lecture, 26 folders
    - Alvarez, Al (Box 4)
    - Delbanco, Nicholas (Box 4)
    - Didion, Joan (Box 4)
    - Doctorow, E.L. (Box 4)
    - Gaddis, William (Box 4)
    - Garrett, George (Box 4)
    - Hall, Donald (Box 4)
    - Heller, Joseph (Box 4)
    - Justice, Donald (Box 4)
    - Lapham, Lewis (Box 4)
    - Kingston, Maxine Hong (Box 4)
    - Kizer, Carolyn (Box 4)
    - Kumin, Maxine (Box 4)
    - Kunitz, Stanley (Box 4)
    - Mailer, Norman (Box 4)
    - Malmud, Bernard (Box 4)
    - Merrill, James (Box 4)
    - Oates, Joyce Carol (Box 4)
    - Percy, Walker (Box 4)
    - Rexroth, Kenneth (Box 4)
    - Sharrar, Jack (Box 4)
    - Simon, John (Box 4)
    - Simpson, Eileen (Box 4)
    - Spender, Stephen (Box 4)
    - Wilbur, Richard (Box 4)
    - Wolfe, Tom (Box 4)
- Lectures and Addresses 1951-1995
  The Lectures and Addresses series, 1951-1995 (0.25 linear ft.), includes drafts and final copies of lectures, addresses, and presentations Aldridge gave at academic conferences, university functions, and memorial services. Included in this series are remarks Aldridge gave at the State University of New York at Potsdam on the work of T. Coraghessan Boyle, as well as his address and notes for a conference at the US Air Force Academy in 1986 celebrating the twenty-fifth anniversary of Joseph Heller's Catch-22.
  - City College "The Outlook for the Future in American Fiction" (Box 4)
  - Columbia University "The Outlook for the Future of American Fiction" (Box 4)
  - Detroit Women Writers (Box 4)
  - "Following After the Lost Generation" (Box 4)
  - Gindin, James Memorial (Box 4)
  - Hayden, Robert Conference (Box 4)
  - Hillsdale College, "The Novel and the Imperial Self" (Box 4)
  - Modern Language Association Convention/Norman Mailer Panel (Box 4)
  - Potsdam Conference, "The Bountifully Talented Mr. Boyle" (Box 4)
  - Powers, Lyall (Box 4)
  - Rice, Warner (Box 4)
  - Squires, James Radcliffe Memorial (Box 4)
  - University of Michigan Alumni Association, "The American Novel" (Box 4)
  - University of Michigan English Department Emeriti Luncheon (Box 4)
  - University of Michigan, Presidents' Club Spring Weekend, "What Makes a Best Seller?" (Box 4)
  - University of Vermont, "Education at the University of Vermont--Four Years of What?" (Box 4)
  - US Air Force Academy Catch-22 Conference (Box 4)
- Scrapbooks 1947-1992
  The Scrapbooks series, 1947-1992 (1 linear ft.), includes seven scrapbooks assembled by Aldridge containing clippings of reviews of his published works.
  - 1947-1952 (Box 5)
  - 1953-1956 (Box 5)
  - 1956-1959 (Box 5)
  - 1959-1961 (Box 5)
  - 1963 (Box 5)
  - Undated, 2 volumes (Box 5)
- Teaching 1948-1991
  Materials in the Teaching series, 1948-1991 (2.5 linear ft.), document Aldridge's long teaching career and scholarship on the contemporary American novel. This series is divided into five subseries: administrative materials, assignments, course descriptions and syllabi, lecture/class notes, and students.
  - Administrative Materials
    The administrative materials subseries documents Aldridge's academic appointments at different institutions, and contains his curriculum vitae, teaching evaluations, and teaching-related correspondence. The assignments subseries includes copies of final exams for courses taught by Aldridge, as well as preliminary exam questions. The course descriptions and syllabi subseries has copies of the course descriptions, syllabi, and class schedules for the English courses Aldridge taught over the course of his career and documents his evolving approach to his courses on the contemporary novel. The lecture/class notes subseries is the largest in the teaching series, and contains notes, drafts, and completed lectures on a wide range of topics including modernism and postmodernism, writers between the world wars, politics and literature, and the state of the American novel, as well as lectures on individual authors.
    - Academic Appointments, 7 folders
      - Hollins College (Box 6)
      - New York University (Box 6)
      - Princeton (Box 6)
      - Queens College (Box 6)
      - University of Copenhagen (Box 6)
      - University of Michigan (Box 6)
      - University of Vermont (Box 6)
    - Correspondence (Box 6)
    - Curriculum Vitae (Box 6)
    - Evaluations (Box 6)
    - Reports (Box 6)
    - Research Partnership Application (Box 6)
    - Salary (Box 6)
    - University of Houston (Box 6)
    - United States Educational Commission for France (Box 6)
  - Assignments
    - Final Exams (Box 6)
    - Preliminary Exam Questions (Box 6)
  - Course Descriptions and Syllabi
    - English 539, "Classic Contemporary Novel" (Box 6)
    - Syllabi and Course Schedules (Box 6)
  - Lecture/Class Notes
    - American Fiction 1920-1958 (Box 6)
    - American Novel (Box 6)
    - Austen, Jane (Box 6)
    - Background of Modernism (Box 6)
    - Barth, John Simmons (Box 6)
    - Beat Generation (Box 6)
    - Beckett, Samuel (Box 6)
    - Burns, John Horne (Box 6)
    - Browning, Robert (Box 6)
    - Camus, Albert (Box 6)
    - Capote, Truman & McCullers, Carson (Box 6)
    - Conrad, Joseph, 4 folders
      - Chance (Box 6)
      - General (Box 6)
      - Heart of Darkness (Box 6)
      - Under Western Eyes (Box 6)
    - Conrad, Joseph & Joyce, James (Box 6)
    - DeLillo, Don (Box 6)
    - Didion, Joan (Box 6)
    - Dostoevsky, Fyodor (Box 6)
    - Eliot, T.S. (Box 6)
    - Ellison, Ralph (Box 6)
    - English 151: Introduction to English Literature (Box 6)
    - "Everyman" (Box 6)
    - Faulkner, William (Box 6)
    - Fitzgerald, F. Scott, 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Flaubert, Gustave (Box 6)
    - Forms of the English Novel (Box 6)
    - Frazer, James George, Marx, Karl and Nietzsche, Friedrich (Box 6)
    - Freud, Sigmund (Box 6)
    - Gide, André (Box 6)
    - Hawkes, John (Box 6)
    - Heller, Joseph, 2 folders
      - Catch-22 (Box 6)
      - Something Happened (Box 6)
    - Hemingway, Ernest, 3 folders
      - A Farewell to Arms (Box 6)
      - General (Box 6)
      - The Sun Also Rises (Box 6)
    - Huxley, Aldous (Box 7)
    - James, Henry, 5 folders
      - The Ambassadors (Box 7)
      - Daisy Miller (Box 7)
      - Early & Middle Period (Box 7)
      - Portrait of a Lady (Box 7)
      - Turn of the Screw (Box 7)
    - Joyce, James, 4 folders
      - Dubliners (Box 7)
      - Portrait of the Artist as a Young Man (Box 7)
      - Ulysses, 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Jung, Carl (Box 7)
    - Kafka, Franz (Box 7)
    - Kosinski, Jerzy (Box 7)
    - Lessing, Dorris (Box 7)
    - Mann, Thomas (Box 7)
    - March, William (Box 7)
    - Metaphysical Poets (Box 7)
    - Modernism (Box 7)
    - Modernism and Postmodernism (Box 7)
    - Nabokov, Vladimir (Box 7)
    - Nietzsche, Friedrich (Box 7)
    - Penn Warren, Robert (Box 7)
    - "The Phoenix" (Box 7)
    - Plath, Sylvia (Box 7)
    - Poetry (Box 7)
    - Politics and Literature (Box 7)
    - Salinger, J.D. (Box 7)
    - Shakespeare, William (Box 7)
    - Styron, William (Box 7)
    - Techniques of Fiction (Box 7)
    - Thirties (Box 7)
    - Tolstoy, Leo (Box 7)
    - Twenties (Box 7)
    - Vonnegut, Kurt (Box 7)
    - Woolf, Virginia (Box 7)
    - World War I and Literature (Box 7)
    - World War II and Literature (Box 7)
    - "Writers of the Two World Wars", 2 folders
      - General (Box 7)
      - Summation (Box 7)
  - Students
    - Graduate Students (Box 7)
- Topical Files 1967-2003
  The Topical Files series, 1967-2003 (0.25 linear ft.), includes a variety of materials that Aldridge segregated into separate files within his personal papers. Subjects in the topical files series include Leslie (Felker) Aldridge (Aldridge's third wife), Eileen Bender, Alan Cheuse, the Norman Mailer Society, Charles Keller Watson, and the National Humanities institute.
  - Aldridge (Felker), Leslie (Box 7)
  - Bender, Eileen (Box 7)
  - Cheuse, Alan (Box 7)
  - National Humanities Institute (Box 7)
  - Norman Mailer Society (Box 7)
  - Watson, Charles Keller (Box 7)
- USIA/ Special Ambassador 1971-1974